# **Muhammad Akbar**

# **Software Engineer - Backend**

Yogyakarta, Indonesia | +6281228467465 | mohammadakbaar11@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github

#### **SUMMARY**

Tech Enthusiast with a specialty as a Backend Engineer who loves to teach. Currently, I have more than three years of working experience as a software engineer in a professional field. I started my professional career as a backend developer back in 2020 and continue my journey to learn more about other tech stacks, especially in the backend world. I am willing to work together as a team or individually and can work everywhere.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Universitas Teknologi Digital Indonesia**

Bantul, DIY

*Majoring in Informatics* 

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Naya Technology | Contract

Sleman, DIY

Backend Engineer

*January 2023 – August 2023* 

- Join the Engineering division.
- Responsible for full development lifecycle designing, developing, testing, deploying, maintaining, monitoring, and improving Autopilot Business Tools. .
- Autopilot Business Tools is designed to help entrepreneurs who have problems with monitoring HR performance, employees coming in and out, being unproductive and by having a dashboard tool that can be used in real time and easily.
- Wrote well-structured and testable code, conducted debugging, addressed bugs, and performed bug fixing with proper solutions.

## **PT.** Indivara Group | Contract

North Jakarta, DKI

Product Technical Specialist / Java Developer

*July 2021 – January 2022* 

- Join the Product Departement.
- Involved in the development of the loyalty exchange platform, enabling merchants to generate loyalty points for their customers and providing an ecosystem for customers to redeem and exchange points at various other merchants using Java, Spring Framework, MyBatis and PostgreSQL.
- Wrote well-structured and testable code, conducted debugging, addressed bugs, and performed bug fixing with proper solutions.
- Collaborated with other engineers including frontend, backend, PM and BA, to solve problems and fulfill filled business needs from clients.

## Praxis Academy | Contract

Yogyakarta, DIY

Backend Engineer / Education Mentor

*June 2019 – April 2021* 

- Teaches about the basics of backend development using Java, which includes data structures, object-oriented principles, design patterns, unit testing, database management, JDBC database access, and ORM, as well as endpoint development using the Spring framework.
- Involve in development of a loyalty management web application utilizing Camunda BPMN and integration with Spring Boot and PostgreSQL database.

#### **PROJECTS**

### • Autopilot Business Tools

*May 2023 - August 2023* 

### **API Master Data Requirements** | May 2023 - September 2023

A master data API acts as a connector to reach the fundamental details within a system. Its primary function in web app development revolves around enabling access to, updating, and syncing this essential data seamlessly. Additionally, it plays a role in verifying data accuracy and ensuring its protection from unauthorized access..

## My responsibilities:

- Implement RESTful API for managing master data like categories, including Companies, Employees, Strategies (vision, mission, values), Perspectives, Goals, SWOTs (Strengths, Weaknesses, Opportunities, Threats), KPIs (Key Performance Indicators), Histories, etc.

Team size: 3 persons

Technologies/Tools: Golang, Gorm, Fiber, PostgreSQL, Docker, Git, Goland IDEA, Postman, Dbeaver, Browser, Gitlab, Telegram

#### • Academic System of Course Institutions

August 2019 - November 2019

**OpenkurSI** | August 2019 - November 2019

OpenkurSI is a web application for academic management of course institutions which includes registration, classes, subject, schedules, attendance, exams, assessments, etc.

#### My responsibilities:

- Design and migrate the database schema
- Implement user management features for account registration and login
- Implement features such as subject, class and assessment management
- Provide endpoint via API

Team size: 5 persons

Technologies/Tools: Java, Micronaut, MariaDB, VS Code, Postman, Dbeaver, Git, Github, Browser, Telegram

## • School Curriculum Management System

November 2019 - February 2020

**STEAM DOM** | November 2019 - February 2020

Web application for schools curriculum management based on the STEAM learning method, containing school management, teachers, students who are members of Steam DOM.

My responsibilities:

- Create from scratch
- Design and migrate the database schema
- Authentication create register user service
- Authentication create login service
- Master data academic API
- Implement schools management

Team size: 10 persons

Technologies/Tools: Java, Micronaut, CockroachDB, Docker, VS Code, Postman, Dbeaver, Gitlab,

Telegram

## **SKILLS**

Language : Java, Go, SQL, NoSQL.

**Backend** : Linux, Spring and Springboot, Micronaut, Fiber, PostgreSQL, MySQL,

MariaDB, MongoDB, RestAPI.

**Platform** : GiHub, GitLab.

**Tools** : Git, Docker, Podman VS Code, Intellij and Goland IDEA, Terminal, Browser,

Postman, Insomnia, DBeaver.

## **CERTIFICATION**

## **Dicoding**

Memulai Pemrograman Dengan Java Issued on September 2021

Credential ID: MRZMKE2NNPYQ Expires on September 2024

## **AWS Academy**

Aws Academy Cloud Operations Issued on December 2023

No expiration date